<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Reuben Liengaard Blog</title>
        <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Reuben Liengaard Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Constructing a 3d egg shape from regular polygons]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/constructing-a-3d-egg-shape-from-regular-polygons</link>
            <guid>constructing-a-3d-egg-shape-from-regular-polygons</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Docusaurus Plushie]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/egg-1-2edd5330f8680fdf901b10dfe36b1e4f.jpg" width="655" height="527" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/egg-2-128d75277af2454dd729a83dce079a5f.jpg" width="1209" height="512" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating a modular circular stage]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/creating-a-modular-circular-stage</link>
            <guid>creating-a-modular-circular-stage</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We were asked to design and build a circular stage for a Cyr wheel performance in Gifford's Circus. The stage had to have a diameter of 6 meters and be able to be broken down into pieces small enough to fit through the 3 meter wide door of the circus tent.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We were asked to design and build a circular stage for a Cyr wheel performance in Gifford's Circus. The stage had to have a diameter of 6 meters and be able to be broken down into pieces small enough to fit through the 3 meter wide door of the circus tent. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-3-f13d41dad830cad645c00222c4afabd5.jpg" width="1018" height="1064" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>It also had to be sturdy enough to support the weight of the performers, but light enough to be easily assembled by two people in a few minutes. The stage had to be flat and level, even on rough ground, and have a system for quickly leveling it. The pieces needed to connect securely and align easily without leaving a bump at the join, as this would interfere with the Cyr wheel. We considered many different patterns for the circle and sought a balance between making the pieces small enough to fit through the door and light enough to carry, but not so small that the stage would be difficult or time-consuming to assemble and have too many joins. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-4-367f329abb10ff4d1f0e1eede7a9c0d6.jpg" width="1041" height="773" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>We also had to consider the number of legs needed for stability and the speed of the leveling process. The stage had to be durable enough to withstand the rough handling and moisture of circus life. We researched various composite panels and ultimately chose one made of an XPS core sandwiched between two layers of glass fiber and coated with a hard, durable floor paint. </p><p>The material was cut into the necessary shapes and had a hot wire cutter with a rectangular profile used to remove the foam from the mating edges, leaving only the outer material. An aluminum extrusion was then bonded to the space with adhesive. The aluminum provided protection for the edge, supported the edge to prevent deflection, and had a slot that accommodated the removable leg structure connecting the panels. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-7-536a8dc3915c3bc552fc3a732e057602.jpg" width="1041" height="773" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-8-27308a0483995332cca67e02fbdec9fc.jpg" width="1058" height="752" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The leg structures were placed at the intersection of three panels and had three pieces of steel box section fitted within the aluminum U channels and welded at 120 degree increments to form a three-directional cross.
<img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-2-96efdfde9bce24cd310ea2c85c3adbb5.jpg" width="1011" height="769" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>A hole was left at the intersection, into which a threaded tube was welded. An internal hex bolt or long grub screw with a foot plate on the bottom was threaded into the tube and could be adjusted from above through a small hole in the stage using an allen key bit on an impact driver. This arrangement allowed for a push-fit assembly process that was fast, and the legs were extended until they touched the ground to level the stage. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-6-2cb158e56730a299f2ecd3b9b490e4ac.jpg" width="1059" height="832" class="img_ev3q"></p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-1-82e129b0df05a3dc89abe4fe84e5cd34.jpg" width="985" height="1547" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>The pieces were held together with inner steel box section curved on the outer curved edge and a large ratchet strap was used to wrap around the entire structure and compress the circle inward, pulling all the pieces together.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/stage-10-ca0b1f0d0eec65bb8455d9793ed7390e.jpg" width="861" height="1302" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[House prices paid by parish]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/house-price-paid-parish</link>
            <guid>house-price-paid-parish</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We used property sale data from the land registry and postal code data from the Ordnance Survey to determine the latitude and longitude coordinates of each house sale. We imported this data into a PostGIS database, ran an SQL query to calculate the average home price for each parish, and used QGIS to visualize the information by coloring the polygons representing each parish based on the average price.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We used property sale data from the land registry and postal code data from the Ordnance Survey to determine the latitude and longitude coordinates of each house sale. We imported this data into a PostGIS database, ran an SQL query to calculate the average home price for each parish, and used QGIS to visualize the information by coloring the polygons representing each parish based on the average price. </p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/price-paid-parish-7dab74e8696d5ee03d431495e4fbf360.jpg" width="1630" height="886" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Manchester Pride - Ruckus wireless heatmap]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/manchester-pride</link>
            <guid>manchester-pride</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[During this deployment, we faced a physically challenging task. We mounted two sectors on the 18th floor of a tower block that was next to the site. From there, we transmitted the signal to multiple wireless point-to-point stations that were attached to temporary structures and buildings within the site. We also provided indoor wireless coverage in an underground parking garage that was used as one of the event venues. We created a heat map of the wireless signal strength in this area. In addition, we established uplinks at various locations to support ticket booths, CCTV cameras, payment terminals for bars, a production office, and emergency liaison cabins.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During this deployment, we faced a physically challenging task. We mounted two sectors on the 18th floor of a tower block that was next to the site. From there, we transmitted the signal to multiple wireless point-to-point stations that were attached to temporary structures and buildings within the site. We also provided indoor wireless coverage in an underground parking garage that was used as one of the event venues. We created a heat map of the wireless signal strength in this area. In addition, we established uplinks at various locations to support ticket booths, CCTV cameras, payment terminals for bars, a production office, and emergency liaison cabins.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modeling a Spherical Solar Concentrator]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/modeling-a-spherical-solar-concentrator</link>
            <guid>modeling-a-spherical-solar-concentrator</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Docusaurus Plushie]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/solar-concentrator-1-ad93c8af9d3ae3260d0f3868784455c9.jpg" width="4592" height="3448" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/solar-concentrator-3-e219fb0426d36846e8be8dc7d33746c2.jpg" width="718" height="521" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/solar-concentrator-4-5274580557a604c66ded0bb0545bc923.jpg" width="1700" height="1610" class="img_ev3q"></p><h1>Modeling a Spherical Solar Concentrator</h1>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Modeling a truss connection]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/modeling-a-truss-connection</link>
            <guid>modeling-a-truss-connection</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Docusaurus Plushie]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/truss-1-262854f9f04c2addb3451e2e0e292058.jpg" width="476" height="442" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/truss-2-246d90b00e94dc787904ed511746731a.jpg" width="4592" height="3448" class="img_ev3q">
<img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/truss-3-c6a73cf924e89c582875520935c6855e.png" width="573" height="324" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[House prices paid parcels]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/house-price-parcels</link>
            <guid>house-price-parcels</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Prepare prices data]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="prepare-prices-data">Prepare prices data<a class="hash-link" href="#prepare-prices-data" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>We combined three separate files containing price paid data into a single file, cleaned and filtered the data by removing quotes, selecting only rows with "GL" followed by a number, printing out only certain columns, adding column names, and deleting rows with null values. We used ogr2ogr to convert a file with cadastral parcel information into a PostgreSQL file, changed the projection from OSGB to WGS84, and imported it into a database. We started a psql session and created empty tables with certain columns in the database. We used the \copy command and SQL JOIN to combine the price and coordinates data based on their shared postcodes, added a column for geometry data, used the latitude and longitude data to create points, and calculated the average value for each of the duplicate polygons. We used QGIS to export the table from the database and modified the layer properties for visual appeal.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/price-paid-parcel-b58fdcacf1b5265bca273e23e59ebb2e.jpg" width="1534" height="787" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>It appears that some of the postal codes are not being properly associated with the intended polygons. For the next project, we will use a set of polygons (parishes) with lower resolution to see if this improves the accuracy of the data.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Royal Windsor Horse Show  wireless heatmap]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/windsor-horse-show</link>
            <guid>windsor-horse-show</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Royal Windsor Horse Show is the largest outdoor horse show in the UK. We provided connectivity to the staff and trader areas. After deployment, a wireless heat map was created by taking geolocated signal strength readings on a smartphone from all over the site. This data was uploaded into ArcGIS and used to create a heat map, which highlighted areas with weak signal strength or wireless black spots. This heat map was overlaid on a georeferenced site map, with the locations of wireless access points, cable routes, and network switch locations marked.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Royal Windsor Horse Show is the largest outdoor horse show in the UK. We provided connectivity to the staff and trader areas. After deployment, a wireless heat map was created by taking geolocated signal strength readings on a smartphone from all over the site. This data was uploaded into ArcGIS and used to create a heat map, which highlighted areas with weak signal strength or wireless black spots. This heat map was overlaid on a georeferenced site map, with the locations of wireless access points, cable routes, and network switch locations marked.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Isle of Wight Festival Asset Tracking Network Hardware]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/isle-of-wight</link>
            <guid>isle-of-wight</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Isle of Wight Festival 2019 took place at Seaclose Park on the Isle of Wight. It was a large site, covering 3km of arenas and fields. Network cabinets were set up in each arena and connected with miles of fiber optic cable. Each cabinet was connected to multiple ADSL connections that were bonded together. Smaller network switches were located within 100m of the cabinet and provided connectivity within the arena. Locations that were beyond the 100m limit for Ethernet were connected with wireless point-to-point links, either from poles attached to the sides of tents or by mounting wireless sectors on cherry pickers that could beam the signal out across the arena, where it could be picked up at distant locations through wireless point-to-point receivers attached to the sides of tents.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Isle of Wight Festival 2019 took place at Seaclose Park on the Isle of Wight. It was a large site, covering 3km of arenas and fields. Network cabinets were set up in each arena and connected with miles of fiber optic cable. Each cabinet was connected to multiple ADSL connections that were bonded together. Smaller network switches were located within 100m of the cabinet and provided connectivity within the arena. Locations that were beyond the 100m limit for Ethernet were connected with wireless point-to-point links, either from poles attached to the sides of tents or by mounting wireless sectors on cherry pickers that could beam the signal out across the arena, where it could be picked up at distant locations through wireless point-to-point receivers attached to the sides of tents.</p><p>This deployment was massive and complex. While we had a site plan and list of locations that needed connectivity, the physical network structure had to be adapted to the site during construction. We had to navigate around obstacles such as roads and areas of the arena that were accessible to the public. Each main cabinet and sub-cabinet needed its own power supply, which we had to coordinate with the electricians on the fly. Sometimes, if they had been to a location before us, we could locate our cabinets near their distribution boxes by following their cables. Other times, they would move the distribution boxes or we would arrive first and they would provide us with one.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/iow-3325f0f9149c141df07e722a42a0281b.png" width="562" height="514" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>At least one cherry picker, equipped with a pan-tilt-zoom CCTV camera, was stationed within each arena. CCTV cameras were also installed on scaffolding poles, gateway arches, and stage sides. All bars needed connectivity for their payment terminals. WiFi was provided in the crew and camping areas, and temporary offices were equipped with temporary WiFi and VoIP phones for both internal and external communication. This was necessary because the cellular network often becomes overloaded with the high number of people at events.</p><p>We utilized QGIS's 'Align Raster' tool to georeference a high-definition image of the site map. We then uploaded this map to Mapbox and created a basic Leaflet.js web map that used the host phone's geolocation to position a marker on the map. This helped us determine our exact location on the map, as physical landmarks were not always visible since the site was under construction. The map helped us identify which tents required connectivity and aided us in orienting ourselves with the site as we walked around.</p><p>We used the 'Map Marker' app on Android to quickly locate network devices as we deployed them. The devices were categorized as AP (access point), SW (switch), RT (router), PTZ (CCTV), VoIP (phone), PTP (point-to-point wireless), and cable types of CAT5 and Fibre. Since the staff members who investigate faults or retrieve hardware after an event are often different from those who deployed it, it can be difficult to locate the devices. A detailed and up-to-date map that shows the locations and connections of all the devices helps to quickly trace faults in the network, which often requires physically searching through tents to find cables.</p><p>When the event was finished, the map was used to quickly locate and retrieve all the equipment.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live network status map for WOMAD 2020]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/womad</link>
            <guid>womad</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Identify areas of flat terrain which receive the most sun]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/flat-sunny</link>
            <guid>flat-sunny</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We imported lidar data into GDAL Grass and used sun shade and slope tools to identify flat areas with above average annual sunlight exposure.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We imported lidar data into GDAL Grass and used sun shade and slope tools to identify flat areas with above average annual sunlight exposure.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hello</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bath Festival - Ruckus wireless heatmap]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/bath-festival</link>
            <guid>bath-festival</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A small deployment of access points was placed around the tents at the Bath Festival. Each access point was connected to a sector on an adjacent building via a point-to-point wireless link, connected to both a ADSL line and a temporary satellite on the roof. Using an Android app, we collected a series of geolocated signal strength data points and formatted them in Excel. This data was then uploaded into ArcGIS, where a tool was used to create a heat map, which was overlayed over the site plan.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A small deployment of access points was placed around the tents at the Bath Festival. Each access point was connected to a sector on an adjacent building via a point-to-point wireless link, connected to both a ADSL line and a temporary satellite on the roof. Using an Android app, we collected a series of geolocated signal strength data points and formatted them in Excel. This data was then uploaded into ArcGIS, where a tool was used to create a heat map, which was overlayed over the site plan.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AONB Permitted Development]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/aonb-permitted-development</link>
            <guid>aonb-permitted-development</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We imported topographic polygons from the OS MasterMap into GIS software, and used the buffer tool to create lines to identify what we could build where. In areas of outstanding beauty, outbuildings over 10m2 in area must be within 20 meters of main dwelling house. We used the buffer tool with a radius of 20 meters on the main dwelling house polygon. If the proposed outbuilding is within 2 meters of the property boundary, it is limited in overall height to only 2.4m. To help us identify the best area to build, we created a buffer around the property boundary. We are allowed to build an outbuilding with a pitched roof up to 4 meters tall (with an eaves height of 2.5 meters) or a flat roof up to 3 meters tall in the area where the buffer around the dwelling house overlaps the inverse of the buffer around the property boundary.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We imported topographic polygons from the OS MasterMap into GIS software, and used the buffer tool to create lines to identify what we could build where. In areas of outstanding beauty, outbuildings over 10m2 in area must be within 20 meters of main dwelling house. We used the buffer tool with a radius of 20 meters on the main dwelling house polygon. If the proposed outbuilding is within 2 meters of the property boundary, it is limited in overall height to only 2.4m. To help us identify the best area to build, we created a buffer around the property boundary. We are allowed to build an outbuilding with a pitched roof up to 4 meters tall (with an eaves height of 2.5 meters) or a flat roof up to 3 meters tall in the area where the buffer around the dwelling house overlaps the inverse of the buffer around the property boundary.</p><h1>AONB Permitted Development</h1><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/permitted-development-229c7618b9d11677141f5f9adf4bbe51.jpg" width="641" height="523" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flood risk analasis for pudding brooke]]></title>
            <link>https://reubenliengaard.github.io/blog/pudding-brook</link>
            <guid>pudding-brook</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Digital Terrain Model LIDAR tiles were imported into QGIS and used to create contour polygons at 0.25m intervals. A graduated style was applied to color the polygons by their elevation. Potential sites for outbuildings were then selected in appropriate high ground locations.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Digital Terrain Model LIDAR tiles were imported into QGIS and used to create contour polygons at 0.25m intervals. A graduated style was applied to color the polygons by their elevation. Potential sites for outbuildings were then selected in appropriate high ground locations.</p><p><img loading="lazy" alt="Docusaurus Plushie" src="/assets/images/pudding-brook-d25c192f63cca338f2a181d2f09cd3e2.jpg" width="1112" height="577" class="img_ev3q"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>hola</category>
            <category>docusaurus</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>